In order to group by day,
要按日期分组的话
we'll need to adjust all the times on April 1, 2017 to read.
我们需要把 2017 年 4 月 1 日这一天所有的时间
2017-04-01 00:00:00. That way,
调整成 2017-04-01 00:00:00
when we group by date, we get every event that occurred for all hours,
按日期分组时 我们会得到
minutes, and seconds of April 1.
4 月1 日所有小时、分钟和秒内发生的每一个事件
They'll all be grouped together into the same grouping.
它们会被归为一组
We can do this using the DATE_TRUNC function.
我们可以用 DATE_TRUNC 函数来完成这个
Let's start by grouping by occurred_at without any truncation.
我们现在开始按 occurred_at 分组 中间不要有任何截断
As you can see, this doesn't help us much at all.
如你所见 这对我们根本没有什么用
If we replace each instance of occurred_at with a truncated version,
如果我们用被截断的版本来替换 occurred_at 的每个实例
we'll get a result set that sums the quantities of standard paper by day.
我们会得到一个结果集 按天汇总了标准纸张的数量
It's important to group by the same metric that's included in
要按包含在 SELECT 语句中的相同度量进行分组 这一点非常重要
the SELECT statement to assure your results are consistent.
这样可以保证你的结果是一致的
In some databases, it's possible to group by a
在一些数据库中 可以用 'year' 来进行分组
'year' but truncate on 'day' in the SELECT statement.
然后在 SELECT 语句中 用 'day' 截断
This is something most people only do by
但是大多数人只能偶尔这么做
accident as it provides results that are confusing and,
因为这样产生的结果会令人困惑
in many cases, wrong for the type of question you're trying to answer.
在很多情况下 你试图回答的问题类型是错误的
The easiest way to make sure you group correctly,
要确保你分组正确 最简单的方法就是
is to use column numbers instead of retyping the exact functions.
用列号而不需重新输入某个准确的函数
DATE_TRUNC can be used to aggregate at very granular levels, like SECOND.
DATE_TRUNC 可以按照更为细粒度的级别进行聚合 如 SECOND
That might be useful if you're working with
如果你正在使用服务器日志 这可能会有用
server logs while many events happen in a given second.
但许多事件发生在给定的秒内
Most of the time though,
虽然大部分时间
you'll use this to aggregate at intervals that makes sense from a business perspective;
你会使用时间间隔进行聚合 因为它从业务角度来看很有意义
day, week, month, quarter, and year.
比如 'day'、 'week'、 'month'、 'quarter'、 'year'
Here we can see different truncations.
在这里 我们可以看到不同的截断
Notice that if our 'month' or 'day' are 01,
需要注意的是 如果我们的 'month' 或 'day' 是 01
there's no change made to these values, as you can see.
你可以看到 这些值没有改变
There are some cases where you might want to just pull out a given part of the date.
在某些情况下 你可能只需要提取一个日期的某一部分
For example, if you want to know what day of
例如 如果你想知道
the week Parch and Posie's website sees the most traffic,
本周哪一天中 Parch &amp; Posie 网站的流量最大
you wouldn't want to use DATE_TRUNC.
但你不想使用 DATE_TRUNC
To get the day of the week,
要想知道具体是哪一天
you'd have to use DATE_PART.
你必须使用 DATE_PART
DATE_PART allows you to pull the part of the date that you're interested in.
DATE_PART 可以让你提取出你感兴趣的日期中的某个部分
But notice that regardless of year,
但是请注意 无论是哪一年
a DATE_PART would provide the same month for an event that
一个 DATE_PART 将会提取出
happens in April 2016 and April 2017,
发生在 2016 年 4 月与 2017 年 4 月 的事件
where a DATE_TRUNC would differentiate these events.
DATE_TRUNC 会区分这些事件
Let's explore this example using Parch and Posie's data.
让我们用 Parch &amp; Posie 的数据来套用一下这个例子
On what day of the week are the most sales made?
一周中的哪一天销售额最多？
Let's start by figuring out the day of the week for each order.
首先 我们要确认每周每天的订单
DOW stands for Day Of Week,
DOW 代表星期几
and returns a value from zero to six,
会返回一个从 0 到 6 的值
where zero is Sunday and six is Saturday.
其中 0 代表星期日 6 代表星期六
Now that we have this column,
现在我们有了这一栏数据
we can aggregate to figure out the day with the most reams of paper sold.
我们可以通过汇总来计算哪一天销售的纸张最多
We'll order it by the sum in descending order so that
我们将按总和降序排列
the day with the most sales will be at the top of the result set.
销售额最高的一天会出现在结果集的顶部
Looks like the most paper was ordered on
看来星期天的纸张订单最大
Sunday and the least paper was ordered on Thursday.
星期四的纸张订单最小